提醒我一下  我为什么要这么做
Remind me, why am I doing this?
因为我在马拉喀什救过你一命
Because I saved your ass in Marrakesh.
是我让你救我的  老头子
Uh, I let you save my ass, old man,
就为了让你给那个你喜欢的
so that you could impress little miss naughty-knickers,
小妞留下好印象
who you had a crush on.
作为一对前间谍
You know, for a couple of ex-spies,
你们听上去更像放春假的联谊会女生
you sound a lot like sorority girls at spring break.
海莉  这是马库斯  他会跟你一起去
Hayley, this is Marcus. He's going in with you.
布莱斯告诉我你挺厉害
Bryce told me you were a badass,
但他没说你是限制级的幻想尤物
but he didn't say you were an X-rated fantasy.
我实在很难被你的魅力所倾倒
It's very hard to focus on how charming you are
因为你的口气像节日的厕所一样
when your breath smells like a festival toilet.
拜托告诉我他的身手
Please tell me he's a better sneak
比泡妞技术好
than he is a pickup artist.
工作很简单  最多就20分钟
A simple job. 20 minutes tops.
我的客户嫁给了
My client is married
曼彻斯特国际能源公司的副总
to the VP of Manchester Energy International --
保罗·霍斯顿
Paul Halston.
她确定他在偷情
She's convinced he's cheating.
所以  马库斯会搞定大楼安保措施
So, Marcus will bypass building security,
海莉去在他办公室的电脑上装好间谍软件
while Hayley puts spyware on his office computer.
好了  我们走吧
All right. Let's do this.
再次感谢  我欠你个人情
Thanks again. I owe you.
当然了
Yes, you do.
这是什么间谍软件啊
What kind of spyware is this?
上传好慢
It's taking forever to upload.
这里是我的办公室
This is my office.
好漂亮啊  天呐
It's so fancy. Oh, my goodness.
看啊  我就坐那儿
Look at that. That's where I sit.
这才叫安全漏洞呢
Talk about a breach of security.
我可是很想突破她的安保
I'd like to breach hers, that's for sure.
你不行
You cannot.
我可以
Yes, I can.
太酷了
That's so cool.
这样才对嘛
I guess it's only fair, right?
你要给我看吗
You gonna show me?
他可远远配不上她
She's way out of his league.
你也是
And yours, by the way.
好看吗
Is this nice?
我赌10块他都
10 bucks he can't even figure out
不会脱那衣服
how to get that thing off.
我就不下注了
Pass.
没事啦
It's okay.
-好了  给  我们走  -等等
- All right. Here, let's go. - Hold on.
他们刚进入有趣的部分
They're just getting to the good part.
我要走了
I'm leaving.
你起得好早  睡得好吗
You're up early. Sleep okay?
不不不
No, no, no, no. No.
我打鼾了吗
Oh, did I snore?
嗯  但问题不在那里
Yeah, but that's not the problem.
那是什么
What was?
你背叛了我
You betrayed me.
什么  怎么说  什么时候
What? How? When?
昨晚  在我梦里
Last night, in my dreams.
但那...我...怎么会...
But that's -- I-I -- What's, uh -- How --
我究竟做了什么罪大恶极的事
What could I have possibly done that was so wrong?
算了
You know what? Never mind.
我不想再经历一遍
I-I don't even want to relive it.
严格讲  你没经历  那是做梦
Well, technically, you didn't live it. You just dreamed it.
但我...
That's -- But I...
不管我做了什么  我很抱歉
Whatever I did, I am so sorry.
是分局打来的
It's the precinct.
我为什么觉得一桩凶案刚刚救了我一命
Why do I feel like - a murder just saved my life?
好了  女士们  我已经决定
Okay, ladies, I have decided
我要改下我的签名
that I should change my autograph.
怎么样
So...what do you think?
奶奶  那个跟你平时的签名没区别啊
Gram, that looks exactly like your usual autograph.
不不不
No, no, no, no, no.
我平时的签名
My usual autograph,
当我还只是个演员时的签名
when I am merely an actress,
是这样的  挺随意  古怪的
is like this, sort of carefree and -- and whimsical,
而另一个  则很有内涵和智慧
whereas the other conveys insight, wisdom.
两者完全不同  看不出来吗
They're completely different. Can't you see that?
-内涵  -智慧
- Insight. - Wisdom.
-是啊  -当然了
- Sure. - Yes, absolutely.
好样的
Good job.
好了  失陪一下
Now, if you'll excuse me,
我还要经营生意
I have a business to run,
尤其鉴于那个谁根本指望不上
especially since you-know-who is completely useless.
我听到了
I heard that.
如果我根本指望不上  贝克特为什么
And if I'm so useless, why would Beckett ask me
要让我参谋一桩凶案呢
to consult on a murder?
-母亲  新签名啊  -是的
- Oh, Mother, new autograph. - Yeah.
不错  很有智慧和内涵
Nice. Conveys wisdom, insight.
我喜欢
I like it.
好了  我拿上车钥匙
All right, I just need my car keys,
这就去曼彻斯特能源大厦了
and I'm off to the Manchester Energy building.
等等  曼彻斯特能源发生了凶案
Wait, murder at Manchester Energy?
被害人是谁
Who's the victim?
只知道是"男性被害人"
All they said was "dead male."
要知道  里克  我还从未亲眼见过你在
You know, Rick, I have never seen you in action
纽约警局的犯罪现场侦查呢
at an NYPD crime scene.
或许你想一起跟来
Well, perhaps you'd like to tag along
看看犯罪现场绝地大师干活儿吗
and watch the crime-scene Jedi master at work.
拜托告诉我你不那么自称吧
Please tell me you do not refer to yourself as that.
真的假的
Do you really?
或许你还是下次再来吧
Perhaps you should come watch another time.
不不  走吧  卡塞尔·旺·肯诺比
No, no, no. Lead on, Castle Wan Kenobi.
你是我唯一的希望
You are my only hope.
这句不错  留着
I like that, but save it.
回头当着他们的面说
Say it in front of the guys.
海莉  怎么回事
Hayley, what happened?
你是赌输了  不得不跟着
Did you lose a bet, and now Castle gets
卡塞尔到处跑吗
to drag you everywhere he goes?
恰恰相反
Quite the contrary.
海莉是想看我再破一案
Hayley actually wanted to watch me solve yet another murder.
你是指帮忙吧  你帮忙破案
You mean help solve. You...help.
记住  哥们  没了我们  你是不可能破案的
Yeah, remember, bro, you cannot solve a homicide without us.
而我们没你是绝对可以破案的
While we sure as hell can solve one without you.
是吗  因为来的路上
Really? Because on the ride over here,
里克好顿吹嘘说纽约警局破不了案呢
Rick was bragging about how the NYPD can't close a case.
那都只是玩笑话
Eh, t-those were just jokes that --
如果不看语境就没那么好玩了
Out of context, it's not as funny.
我说的时候还翻白眼来着
I was rolling my eyes when I said it.
多谢你背后捅刀啊
Thank you for stabbing me in the back.
你不是唯一背后挨刀的
You weren't the only one.
被害人背后
Our victim took his
这刀插在T4  T5椎骨之间
right between his T4 and T5 vertebrae.
脊髓被切断  即刻死亡
Severed his spinal cord. Died instantly.
看他的外套  不是员工喽
I'm guessing from his outfit, he wasn't an employee?
很可能是个贼
Most likely some kind of thief.
还挺厉害
Pretty good one at that.
安保系统完全没有被触动
None of the security was tripped.
监控都被关闭了
All the cameras were shut down.
有什么失窃的吗
Was anything stolen?
有什么好偷的
What's there to steal?
这是一家能源公司大楼
I mean, this is an energy-company office building.
唯一有价值的就是家具和电脑
The only thing of value are the furniture and the computers.
我可以看看吗
May I?
显然  我们完全无助
Clearly, we're helpless.
来吧  卡塞尔  替我们破案吧
So, come on, Castle, please, solve this case for us.
我们唯一确定的
Well, the only thing we know for sure is --
他死在凌晨3:27
He was killed at 3:27 a.m.
很不错啊  海莉
Very good, Hayley.
等等  什么  你怎么知道
Wait. What? How did you know that?
表砸坏了
Broken watch.
肯定是摔倒时撞坏了
He must have busted it when he hit the ground.
埃斯波西托  我们有海莉啊
Esposito, we have Hayley.
-还要卡塞尔做什么  -是啊
- What do we need Castle for? - Yeah.
这好笑
Super funny, guys.
那只是走运  我还是能帮忙确定被害人身份的
That was lucky, and I can still help I.D. this victim,
非常感谢
thank you very much.
蕾妮  查下指纹
Lanie, run a fingerprint scan.
听着  卡塞尔
Okay, look, Castle,
我不知道这是怎么回事
I don't know what all of this is about,
但我没教你写书
but I don't tell you how to write your books,
你也别叫我怎么查身份
so don't tell me how to I.D. a body.
我已经进行了扫描
I've already performed a scan.
我在等结果呢
I'm just waiting for the results.
你觉得可以靠这个薄荷糖的购买
Uh, do you think it's possible to identify the victim
确认死者身份吗
from the purchase of these mints?
是可以
I guess we could.
比扫描指纹要高效多了
It's far more efficient to use a fingerprint scanner.
我污染了证物
I-I just bolloxed up a piece of evidence.
-真抱歉  -太菜了  是吧
- I'm so sorry. - Rookie move, right?
因为你从未在犯罪现场乱碰过
Because you've never touched anything at a crime scene.
记下这个上面沾了海莉的指纹
Make note that this is contaminated with Hayley's prints.
真抱歉
So sorry.
好了  有死者身份了
Oh, here we go. We got an I.D. on our victim.
名叫马库斯·雅尼克
His name is Marcus Janek.
是个窃贼
He's, uh, yeah -- a second-story man
有一系列前科
with a history of priors.
看来有人抓了马库斯现行便杀了他
Looks like somebody caught Marcus in the act and killed him.
或许马库斯有个搭档
Or perhaps Marcus had a partner.
搭档
Partner?
马库斯是个盗贼  他应该很警觉
Well, Marcus is a burglar. He would be on high alert.
而他能让人走到他背后
The only reason he'd let someone behind him
肯定是因为信任对方  就是搭档喽
is if he trusted that person, I.E. a partner.
我们找到跟马库斯一起闯进来的人
We find the person Marcus broke in here with,
就能找到凶手
we find his killer.
厉害啊  卡塞尔
Very good, Castle.
是啊  讲得通
Yeah, that makes a lot of sense.
你们为什么一副很惊讶的样子
Why are you acting surprised?
不知是否重要
I don't know if it's important at all,
但所有椅子都放进去摆好的  除了那个
but all those chairs are tucked in, except for that one.
除了那边那个
Except for that one there.
是啊  我也注意到了
Yep, I noticed that, too.
早在她之前  进来时就发现了
On the way in, way before she did.
那么  奈德·沃纳
So, Ned Werner.
或许奈德昨晚加班了
Perhaps Ned was working late last night.
或许看到了什么
Maybe he saw something,
或许他是马库斯的搭档  内应
or maybe he's Marcus' partner, an inside man.
有请  莱恩警探
Please, Detective Ryan.
多谢  埃斯波西托警探
Thank you, Detective Esposito.
你们先请
After you boys.
喂
Hello?
布莱斯  马库斯死了
Bryce, Marcus is dead.
怎么回事
What the hell is going on?
这跟你的客户有关吗
Does this have anything to do with your client?
海莉  对不起
Hayley, I'm sorry.
我撒谎了
I lied about everything.
-根本没有出轨的丈夫或是愤怒的妻子  -什么
- There is no cheating husband, nor an angry wife. - What?
你怎么能...
How could you be so --
我别无选择
I had no choice.
为什么  谁叫你这么做的
Why? Who put you up to this?
无所谓了  现在都无所谓了
It doesn't matter. Not anymore.
你只需要知道代号44
All you need to know is Code 44.
对不起  海莉  真的很抱歉
I'm sorry, Hayley. I'm so sorry.
海莉  他们想...
Hey, Hayley, the guys are thinking that...
-一切都好吗  -不好
- Everything okay? - Uh, no.
我一个朋友病了
A friend of mine's fallen ill,
我得去看看
and, um, I've got to swing by, check in.
好
Of course.
该死  阿丽克西斯  你来干什么
Damn it, Alexis. What are you doing here?!
我需要那些文件工作用
Well, I needed some case files for work.
但如果有人不请自来你就会这样
But if this is how you get when people come over unannounced,
我很乐意把备用钥匙还你
I am happy to give you back your spare key.
起来吧
Come on.
在重装修吗
So, uh, redecorating?
你得马上离开
You need to leave now.
我知道怎么回事
I see what's going on.
你拿了你的行李袋  和枪
You've got your go-bag, your guns.
这是你想去那个犯罪现场的原因吗
Is this why you wanted to go by that crime scene?
海莉  如果你有麻烦了  告诉我
Hayley, if you're in trouble, talk to me.
我不能  不安全
I can't. It's not safe.
好吧  听着  我昨晚帮了个朋友个忙
Okay, look, I did a favor for a friend last night --
至少  我当他是个朋友
at least, I thoughthe was a friend.
本该是个简单的私家侦探任务
It was meant to be a quick P.I. job,
但严格讲  我违背了法律
but technically, I broke a few laws.
好吧  告诉贝克特  告诉我爸
Okay, well, tell Beckett. Tell my dad.
-他们可以帮忙  -不行
- They can help. - No, they can't.
跟我合作的那个朋友  曾是我军情六处的同事
The friend I was working with -- We were in MI6 together.
他刚刚打来
He just phoned.
原来这趟活儿并不普通
It turns out that the job wasn't legit.
有更大的阴谋
Something bigger is going on,
而且严重到他对我说了代号44
something bad enough that he told me to go Code 44.
那是什么意思
Uh, what does Code 44 mean?
意思是抛弃一切  每个人
It means abandon everything and everyone.
马上逃命  不要回头看
It means run for your life and don't look back.
你不能那么做
You can't do that.
-我别无选择  -你有的
- I have no choice. - Yes, you do.
你居无定所那么多年
After years of floating from one place to the next,
你终于在这里找到了真正的家
you've finally found a real home here.
如果我留下就可能将你和这个家置于危险中
And I might be putting you and it in danger by staying.
我必须得马上走
I have to go now.
不  你该留下  抵抗
No, you have to stay and fight,
搞清楚究竟怎么回事  控制局面
figure out what's really going on here and fix it.
至少试试吧
Please at least try.
先生们好啊
Hello, gentlemen.
卡塞尔  你现在不该来这里
Castle, you shouldn't show your face around here right now.
是啊  贝克特很生气
Yeah. Beckett's pissed.
各位  就是个梦而已
Uh, guys, it was a dream.
梦是通往潜意识的大门  卡塞尔
Well, dreams are doorways to the subconscious, Castle.
嗯  你做的事又太...
Yeah. And what you did was just so...
过分了
...wrong.
她跟你们说了我做了什么  我做了什么啊
She told you what I did? What did I do?
我们发誓保密的  哥们
Well, we're sworn to secrecy, bro.
是啊  不像某些人  我们绝不会背叛贝克特
Yeah. Unlike some, we would never do that to Beckett.
就是个梦啊
It was a dream.
不管是不是梦  你在现实中做了什么
Well, dream or not, you did something in real life,
而贝克特的潜意识有所察觉
and Beckett's subconscious is picking up on it.
你得想明白究竟是什么
You need to figure out what that was
然后趁还来得及赶紧交待
and come clean before it's too late.
-奈德来了  -走吧
- Here's Ned. - Let's go.
你朋友怎么样了
How's your friend doing?
是啊  好多了  谢谢
Oh, uh, much better, thanks.
我现在有些好奇了
You know, my curiosity's been piqued.
我们可以看看他的审讯吗
Can we watch his interview?
好啊  等到...
Oh, sure. Just wait till...
好了  走吧
Okay, go.
沃纳先生  告诉我们
So, Mr. Werner, tell us where you were
你凌晨3点到4点间在哪
3:00 and 4:00 a.m. this morning.
在家  一个人睡觉
Home. Alone, asleep.
好奇怪  奈德  因为你的办公室电脑
Well, that's weird, Ned, because your office computer
显示你3:02还登录进去来着
says that you logged in at 3:02 a.m.,
就在凶案发生前几分钟
just minutes before the murder.
等等  对了
Oh, wait. Yeah, no. Yes, yes.
我...你们一提  我想起来了
I was, uh -- Now that you mention it, yes, I did.
我去了办公室一趟
I-I popped into the office for a bit,
做点工作
just to do some work.
我没在那儿见到他
I did not see him there.
你当时一个人在办公室吗
So you were in the office alone?
是的  绝对一个人
Yeah, completely alone.
你个撒谎的混蛋
You lying, little bastard.
你为什么认为他说他是一个人是撒谎
What makes you think he's lying about being alone?
看他的脖子
Look at his neck.
看到那个小吻痕了吗  是新的
See that tiny love bite? It's new.
如果奈德昨晚都是一个人  那是谁留下的
So if Ned was alone last night, who gave him that?
你在撒谎吗  奈德
Are you lying to us, Ned?
没有  我不会撒谎的
No. No, I would not lie.
绝不会
Never. No, no.
你说没过去就撒谎了
You lied about not being there.
我没有
No, I didn't. I didn't lie.
-我只是忘了  -只是忘了
- I just forgot. - Oh, you forgot?
那或许你还忘记了别的
So maybe there's something else you forgot.
或许你忘记了跟马库斯搭档  放他进去
Maybe you forgot that Marcus was your partner and you let him in.
-忘记你杀了他  -没有
- And you forgot that you killed him. - No.
-你记得杀了他喽  -是的
- So you remember killing him? - Yes.
-太棒了  -等等  不是的
- That's perfect. - Wait! No, no, no, no, no!
是的  我没忘
Yes, yes, yes, I didn't forget,
我没杀他
because, no, I didn't kill him.
我不认识这人
Look, I don't know this man.
我从未见过他
I've never seen him before in my life,
我不可能杀他
so I couldn't have killed him.
你的办公室电脑显示你3:10分登出电脑
So, your office computer says you logged out at 3:10 a.m.
而他是3:27被杀的
He was killed at 3:27 a.m.
其实  你是有可能杀他的
Actually, you could have killed him.
是啊
Yeah.
等等  3:27
Wait. 3:27?
不不  我不可能杀了他
No, no, no. I could not have killed him,
因为我当时已经搭上顺风车了
because I was in a Hytch ride by then.
瞧  司机3:19接我走的
See? Driver picked me up at 3:19 a.m.
你好  奈德  我们聊聊吧
Hello, Neddie. Let's have a chat, shall we?
你是警察吗
Are you a cop?
那个警探说我可以走了
The other detective said I was free to go!
还没呢
Not quite.
好吧
Okay, okay, okay!
好  我会的  好
Yes, yes, I will. Yes!
怎么回事
What the hell is going on in here?
这位先生要修改他的供述
Well, this gentleman would like to revise his statement.
是的  我想修改我的供述
Yes, I'd like to revise my statement.
我不是一个人在办公室
I was not alone in my office.
大概凌晨2点  在一家酒吧
Uh, about 2:00 a.m., in a bar,
我遇见了一个美得冒泡的金发妞
I met a smoking-hot blond chick.
她是位年轻可爱的女士  叫卡拉
Who -- She's a very lovely young lady named Karla,
我们一拍即合  于是我把她带回了我的办公室
and we hit it off, so I took her back to my office.
你为什么对我的警探撒谎
So, why did you lie to my detectives?
因为这样的安全疏漏
Because a security breach like this
会害淫荡奈德被解雇
could get nasty Ned here fired.
说啊  告诉好警监你做了什么
Go on, tell the nice captain what you did.
我想让卡拉觉得我了不起
I was trying to impress Karla,
所以
so I...
我登录进了公司的封闭服务器
I logged into the company's closed server,
然后给唐宁街10号断了一会儿电
and I shut down the power at 10 Downing Street for a second.
但没成功
It didn't work, though.
我们都没做爱
We didn't have sex or nothing.
令人震惊
Shocking.
不  她本来对我很热情
No. She was very frisky with me.
然后  突然
And, then, all of a sudden,
她就说自己烦了  想回家
she said she was bored, wanted to go home.
为什么
Why?
我觉得可能是因为
I think maybe it was because
我当时解不开她的束胸
I was having trouble undoing her corset.
我要为自己说一句  那东西特别复杂
In my defense, it was, like, crazy-complicated,
我...
and -- and -- and I was -- I was --
我又很紧张
I was very nervous.
所以你是登录上电脑后卡拉才离开的吗
So after you logged on to your computer is when Karla left you?
是的  就我所知
Yes. And as far as I know,
我离开时办公室里可没人
the office was completely empty when I left.
你看到卡拉离开大楼了吗
Did you actually see Karla leave the building?
没有
N-No.
那么她可能藏了起来  等到你离开吗
So it's possible she hid and then waited until you left?
莱恩  奈德要修改他的供述
Hey, Ryan, Ned here wants to revise his statement.
太棒了  出了点事故吗
Awesome. Had a little accident?
什么都别碰
Don't touch anything, please.
等等  海莉
Uh, excuse me, Hayley.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
各位  有什么问题吗
Hey, guys. Is there a problem here?
海莉给奈德上了水刑
Hayley waterboarded Ned.
我才没有  就是马桶冲头而已
I did no such thing. It was more of a swirly.
算了
Never mind.
显然  奈德被一个
Look, apparently, Ned was tricked
叫卡拉的女人骗了
by some woman named Karla
让她进入了大楼
into gaining access to the building
还得以使用一台安全服务器
and the secured server,
很可能是为帮马库斯抢劫那里
most likely to help Marcus rob the place.
是啊  但马库斯和卡拉之间
Yeah, but clearly something happened
显然是出了什么事
between Marcus and Karla,
因为看来是她
because it looks like she's the one
把刀捅进了他的背后
that drove that knife into his back.
就这样吗
And is that all?
你问我做什么
Why are you asking me?
因为你显然不太对劲  海莉
Because clearly something is going on with you, Hayley --
跟此案有关
something connected to this case.
你可以告诉我们的
You know, you can tell us.
我昨晚也在那个办公室
I was in that office last night.
好吧  我们得谈谈了
Okay, we need to talk now.
不是吧  你想在这儿谈
Really? You want to talk in here?
是的  我们都在这里审讯凶案嫌犯
Yes. This is where we question all of our murder suspects.
你觉得我杀了马库斯
You think I killed Marcus.
现在  我不知道该怎么想
Right now, I don't know what to think.
我军情六处一个老朋友  布莱斯·罗伯茨
An old friend of mine from MI6, Bryce Roberts,
雇了我和马库斯执行私家侦探任务
hired me and Marcus to do some P.I. work,
向曼彻斯特能源公司
to install some spy software
副总的电脑上安装间谍软件
on the VP of Manchester Energy's computer.
至少  我以为是那么回事
At least, that's what I thought we were doing.
而我们干到一半  奈德和卡拉走了进来
Right in the middle of it all, in walked Ned and Karla,
于是我干完了我该干的  就走了
so I finished my part of the job, and I took off.
马库斯留了下来  想看奈德和卡拉干柴烈火
Marcus stayed to watch Ned and Karla go at it.
那肯定是他们计划好的
Must have been part of their plan.
等等  马库斯和卡拉是搭档吗
Wait a minute. Marcus and Karla were partners?
肯定是的
Must have been.
但他们究竟想要什么  以及她为何下杀手
Although what they were really after and why she killed him,
我就不知道了
I have no bloody idea.
好吧  跟我说说布莱斯
Okay. Tell me about Bryce.
我为军情六处做兼职时  他是我的领队
He was my team leader back when I freelanced for MI6.
你们关系好吗
Were you guys close?
是的  有一阵吧
Yeah, for a while.
然后一次行动中  出了大岔子
Then everything went to hell in an op,
我就跟军情六处彻底告别了
and I cut all ties with MI6.
几个月前
Then, a few months ago,
他退休了
he retired from Her Majesty's service,
在纽约建立了一家自由安保公司
started a freelance security company here in New York.
又跟我联络上了
He got back in touch.
他是个好人
He's a good man.
那他为什么要叫上你
So, why did he involve you?
是啊  我也想问呢
Yeah, I'd like to ask him that myself.
知道我们能在哪找到他吗
Any idea where we can find him?
你确定布莱斯的前妻还住这里吗
Are you sure Bryce's ex-wife still lives here?
希望是
I hope so.
他消失之前应该
He would have come to say goodbye
会来道个别
before he went Code 44.
这里没车
There's no cars here.
看上去没人
It doesn't look like anybody's --
警察
Police!
多严重
How bad?
有尸体
We got a body here.
-好吧  -布莱斯
- All right. - Bryce?
布莱斯
Bryce?
背后中刀  跟马库斯一样
Stabbed in the back, just like Marcus.
T4和T5椎骨之间
Right between the T4 and T5 vertebrae.
我看不是巧合
I don't believe it's coincidence.
节哀顺变
I'm sorry about your friend.
谢谢
Thanks.
你不能自责
You know, you can't blame yourself for this.
布莱斯撒谎了  他骗了你
Bryce lied. He chose to trick you.
布莱斯受了胁迫
Bryce was leveraged, compromised.
被谁呢
Yeah, but by whom?
他们究竟把你搅进了什么里
Hey, what are they getting you mixed up in?
警员在这一带进行排查
Yo, some unis are canvassing the neighborhood,
但没有嫌疑人的痕迹
but there's no trace of our suspect.
肯定是卡拉
It had to be Karla.
或许她在收尾
Could be she's cleaning up loose ends.
她的搭档都死了
I mean, her partners are dead.
卡拉现在只需要消失了
All Karla has to do now is disappear.
她为什么要闯入曼彻斯特能源大楼呢
Why would she break into Manchester Energy building in the first place?
他们想要什么
What were they after?
他们为什么要扯上海莉呢
And why do they need Hayley to be a part of it?
等等
Wait. Hang on.
我的银行账户刚入账了一千万
$10 million was just wired into my bank account
来自曼彻斯特能源公司
from Manchester Energy.
怎么回事
What the hell is going on?
我想我知道他们为什么需要你了  海莉
I think I know why they needed you, Hayley.
为什么
Why?
你是替罪羊
You're the patsy.
我们得到确证
We are getting confirmation
伦敦的大面积停电
that the massive blackout that has hit London
与针对曼彻斯特国际能源公司的网络攻击有关
is due to a cyber attack on Manchester Energy International,
这家电气公司
an electric and gas company
在欧洲和美国都有办事处
with offices in Europe and in the United States.
你账户里的钱就是
The money in your account is the noose
把网络攻击套在你脖子上的绞索
that hangs the cyber attack around your neck.
城市电网
It may take weeks before
完全恢复可能要几周时间
they're able to restore full power to the city's grid.
我以为布莱斯说的是实话呢
I just assumed that Bryce was telling the truth.
我怎么能那么蠢
How could I have been so stupid?!
布莱斯给了你一个U盘  是吧
It was a thumb drive Bryce gave you, wasn't it?
天呐  那肯定是个病毒
Oh, God. I must have had a virus of some sort.
我联络了联调局
So, I spoke with the FBI,
他们将此举视为恐怖袭击
and they are considering this an act of terror.
损害多严重
How bad's the damage?
伦敦可能要
Uh, it's gonna be a few days
好几天甚至更久才能恢复电力
before the power's back up in London, maybe more.
太好了  那么我有意将我的家乡
Fantastic. So I have unwittingly plunged my hometown
送回了16世纪
back into the 16th century.
这可能不完全是坏事
Oh, that might not be all that bad.
《哈姆雷特》就是16世纪时写就的
I mean, Hamlet was written in the 16th century.
我是在帮倒忙
I'm not helping.
凯特  他们知道我也参与了吗
Kate, do they know about my involvement yet?
他们追查到汇入你账户的钱了
They traced the money to your account,
现在有逮捕你的通缉令
and there is a warrant out for your arrest.
打扰
Excuse me.
海莉  这是卡拉吗
Hayley, uh, is this Karla?
是的  那是我们的老朋友奈德
Oh, yes, with our old friend Ned.
街对面的监控拍到了他们
Well, the security camera across the street caught them
离开这家酒吧  去往办公室
leaving this bar on their way to the office.
酒保记得卡拉
The bartender remembers Karla,
但那晚之前他从未见过她
but he'd never seen her before that night,
不幸的是  是奈德付了账
and unfortunately, Ned paid the bill.
-那么我们无法找她  -我们在彻查
- So we have no way to track her. - Well, we're scrubbing
布莱斯和马库斯的电脑和手机
Bryce and Marcus' computers and cellphones.
他们其中一位肯定跟她有联络
One of them had to have been in contact with her.
别担心  我们会找到她的
Don't worry. We'll find her.
听着  我们会有事通知你
Look, we'll keep you in the loop,
但警局大概是最不合适
but a police precinct is probably the worst place
躲避联调局的地方了
to hide from the feds.
我们可以回私家侦探社
Well, we can go back to the P.I. office.
你可以躲在应急室
You can stay out of sight in the panic room
直到我们帮你洗脱罪名
until we clear your name.
不行  我不能让你们给我打掩护
No. I can't let you guys cover for me.
不  我们会罩你的
No, we got your back.
走吧
Just go.
有多糟糕
So, how bad is it?
她要能脱罪  那真是奇迹
She's gonna need a miracle to stay out of jail.
我要是记得她的什么特征就好了
I wish I remembered something about her --
纹身  伤疤
a tattoo, a scar.
说来好笑
You want a laugh?
我唯一记得关于这女人的
The only thing I recall about this woman
就是可怜的奈德怎么也解不开她的束胸
is poor Ned fumbling around with her fancy corset.
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
继续说  是棉的还是蕾丝的
Tell me more. Was it cotton or lace?
真变态
Perv much?
我是认真的
I'm serious.
好吧  是镶着黑色皮革的蕾丝  怎么了
Okay, it was lace with black leather. Why?
缩小了范围  有填充吗
Narrows it down. Padded?
没有
No.
挂扣在前面还是后面
Back or front clasps?
在后面
Back clasps and buckles,
前面纽扣上有一个金属环
and it had a metal ring in the front with snaps.
束胸上有水晶钻吗
Were there crystal studs across the decolletage?
还真有
Actually, yes.
诱惑内衣
La Seductrice.
我找一下2016年"我亲爱的"产品集
Give me a moment to pull up the 2016 Mon Cheri collection.
就是这种  就是这种
That's it. That's the one.
瞧吧  任务完成
And voila. My work here is done.
老爸  我是不是该问一下
Hey, dad should I even ask?
-是为了《妮奇·希特》做的调查  -好吧
- "Nikki Heat" research. - Yeah.
诱惑内衣在纽约只有一家分店
Well, there's only one La Seductrice in New York.
我把这个发给埃斯波和莱恩
I will e-mail this to Espo and Ryan,
看看他们能不能通过束胸衣找到她
see if they can track her down by her unmentionables.
该死
Oh, damn it.
我认识他  他是军情六处的
I recognize him. He's MI6.
看来不光是联邦调查局在查这事
I guess the FBI aren't the only ones investigating.
-你们去应急室躲躲  -好的
- You guys get in the panic room. - Yeah.
你好  卡塞尔先生  我是史蒂芬·马洛里
Hello, Mr. Castle. The name's Stephen Mallory.
是军情六处的马洛里探员吧
Do you mean Agent Mallory, MI6?
你怎么知道
Well, I wonder how you knew that.
瞎猜的  请进
Lucky guess. Do come in.
装修不错
Lovely decor.
复古又不失时尚
Retro but chic.
谢谢
Thank you.
但我想英国特工来这
But I assume Her Majesty's Secret Service
不会是对我的装修感兴趣吧
isn't interested in my interior designer.
当然不是  不过我们对你的生意伙伴挺感兴趣
No. However, your business partner interests us greatly.
我从今天上午就没见过海莉了
Ah, well, I haven't seen Hayley since this morning.
卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle,
我必须尽快找到希普顿女士
I must find Ms. Shipton before it's too late,
否则我就帮不了她了
before I can no longer help her.
海莉离开军情六处是有原因的
Well, Hayley left MI6 for a reason.
我想她不需要你的帮助  马洛里探员
I doubt she needs your kind of help, Agent Mallory.
你可能认为自己了解希普顿女士
You may think you know Ms. Shipton,
但其实你不了解
but, in fact, you do not.
装得可像那么回事
You could have fooled me.
她肯定是骗了你
I'm sure she has.
告诉我
Tell me,
希普顿女士告诉过你她为什么离开军情六处吗
did Ms. Shipton ever tell you why she left MI6?
节日奖金太少  炸鱼薯条不好吃之类的
Something about holiday bonuses and bad fish and chips.
真风趣
Charming.
无论你怎么想
Look, despite what you think,
我敢肯定海莉是被陷害的
I can assure you Hayley was framed.
我也敢肯定  她就是今天
And I can assure you - she is the main conspirator
一切事情的主谋
in everything that happened today.
你怎么能这么确定
How can you be so sure about that?
我能看到她的机密档案
I have access to her confidential dossiers,
卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle.
你一定要相信我
You must trust me --
希普顿女士策划并执行了
Ms. Shipton is intimately involved
今天的事情  她跟这事关系密切
in the planning and the execution of today's events.
我们有证据
We have proof.
别信他的  他所说的
Ignore him. Everything he's saying
都是干情报的惯用伎俩
is classic counterintelligence.
希普顿女士可以说是
Ms. Shipton was arguably
军情六处历史上最残忍  最冷酷的
one of the most ruthless, cold-hearted operatives
特工之一
in the history of MI6.
说实话  在她最后一次行动中
Truth be told, on her final mission,
她为了救自己  而不顾搭档的死活
to save her own skin, she let her own partner die.
我想这已经能够说明
I think that would be an indication
你是在跟什么样的人打交道
of exactly the type of person you're dealing with.
她可能也会这么对你
She might very well do the same to you...
或者对你的女儿
or to your daughter.
我已经说过了  马洛里探员
Well, as I said, Agent Mallory,
我真的不知道海莉现在在哪
as far as where Hayley is, I haven't got a clue.
如果你有线索
Well, if you ever get one,
最好还是给我打电话
it would be in your best interest to call.
为什么说军情六处有你参与的证据
What was all that about MI6 having proof you're behind this?
都是骗人的
It's all lies.
难道他说你搭档的事也是假的吗
Even what he said about your old partner?
那也是骗人的吗
That was a lie, too?
你真的不顾搭档的死活
You let your partner die.
没有  韦斯利的死是因为
No. Wesley died because...
因为...  一言难尽
because... It's complicated.
别让马洛里影响到你们
Look, don't let Mallory get into your head.
你们知道可以相信我的
You know you can trust me.
你提供的束胸线索有回复了
Your tip about the corset paid off.
你们找到卡拉了吗
You found Karla?
我们联系了那家内衣店
We reached out to that lingerie shop
确认了金发女的身份
and I.D.'d our blonde.
她的真名是贝丝·韦恩
Her real name is Beth Wynne.
她是个行骗老手了
She's a longtime grifter who's worked a lot of scams.
有意思
Interesting.
还有  她用另一个化名
And get this -- One of her aliases
刚在肯尼迪机场153号的
just checked into a motel
汽车旅馆登记入住了
at 153rd by JFK.
我们马上赶往那边
We're headed there right now.
如果找到她我们会通知你
We'll let you know if we find her.
好
All right.
你要去哪  你不是该躲起来吗
Where are you going? I thought you were staying out of sight.
她杀了我朋友
She killed my friend.
我要去看她被捕
I'm going to be there for the arrest.
我跟你一起去
Not alone you're not.
海莉  你不该来这的
Hayley, you're not supposed to be here.
但我还是来了
And yet here I am.
卡塞尔  你怎么不拦着她
Castle, you didn't stop her?
我想拦也拦不住
Like I could stop her even if I wanted to.
伙计们  就是她
Hey, hey, hey, guys. That's her.
贝丝·韦恩  纽约警局
Beth Wynne, NYPD.
别跑
Hey! Come here!
贝丝·韦恩
Beth Wynne...
你因谋杀马库斯·雅尼克
you're under arrest
和布莱斯·罗伯茨而被逮捕了
for the murders of Marcus Janek and Bryce Roberts.
不  你们不能抓我
No, no, no. You are not hanging this on me.
我没杀人
I didn't kill anyone.
我离开曼特斯特能源时  马库斯还活着
When I left Manchester Energy, Marcus was alive.
之后我就直接回到这里了
I came straight back here.
你们可以去查旅馆监控录像
You can check - the motel surveillance cameras.
那布莱斯呢
And what about Bryce?
我没杀他  我当时在这里
I didn't kill him. I was here.
我至今都没离开过这里
I haven't even left this place till now.
那昨晚到底发生什么事了
Okay, then what really happened last night?
海莉和马库斯闯进去的时候
What were you doing there
你在做什么
when Hayley and Marcus were breaking in?
我是那个蠢货奈德的诱饵
I was the bait for that idiot Ned.
必须有两个不同的安全码
The computer system required
才能登录那个电脑系统
two separate security keys.
我们无法直接侵入电脑去上传病毒
You can't just hack in and upload a worm.
植入病毒的前提是安全入口开放着
It had to be embedded while a secure portal was open.
所以你得让奈德登录电脑
So you made sure that Ned logged in.
之后  海莉无意中植入的病毒
And after that, the worm that Hayley unintentionally planted
就能大肆破坏伦敦市电网了
was allowed to wreak havoc on London's power grid.
等等  马库斯充其量是个普通的小毛贼
Wait a minute. Marcus was a run-of-the-mill cat burglar at best.
他怎么可能想出这么精密的计划
How would he come up with such an elaborate plan?
他只是在执行命令
He was just following orders.
谁的命令
From who?
一个叫埃德加·帕顿的人
A man named Edgar Patton.
-你从没见过这个人吗  -没见过
- You never met this man? - No.
马库斯是接头人
Marcus was the point man,
是他把我扯进这任务的
and he brought me onto this job.
马库斯有提过他什么吗
Marcus say anything about him?
快点  你肯定知道点什么
Come on, you got to know something.
他应该抽烟  我猜
He's a smoker, I guess.
行动开始前一晚
The night before the job,
马库斯在一家高级俱乐部和埃德加会面
Marcus met Edgar at some fancy club
拿到了病毒程序
to get the worm program.
马库斯回来时
When Marcus came back,
他和他的电脑都有很大的雪茄味
both him and his laptop stunk like cigars,
我只知道这些了
and that's all I know.
马库斯的电脑现在在哪
Where's Marcus' laptop now?
如果这电脑里还有病毒程序的备份
Okay, if there's still a copy of the worm program on here,
我应该能查出这病毒是谁创建的
I might be able to find out who created it.
等等  如果仅仅是为了破坏伦敦市电网
Hold on. To attack London's power grid,
根本都用不着海莉或布莱斯
you didn't even need Hayley or Bryce.
对  但埃德加要求马库斯必须如此
No. But that's the way Edgar told Marcus it had to be.
我是被指定的
I was chosen specifically.
对
Yeah.
你的好哥们布莱斯  只是被用来
And your buddy Bryce was only leveraged to do this job
引你入瓮的
to get to you.
卡拉没撒谎
Our Karla's telling the truth.
旅馆监控录像证明了
Motel security cameras prove
布莱斯死时她在旅馆里
that she was there during Bryce's murder.
蕾妮说布莱斯和马库斯
Lanie says that both Bryce and Marcus
是被同一个人杀的
were stabbed by the same killer,
所以这个埃德加是我们的新头号嫌犯
so it looks like this Edgar guy is our new number-one suspect.
抽雪茄的家伙有什么线索吗
Any leads on the cigar smoker?
还没有  我们会检查全城的雪茄俱乐部
Not yet. We're gonna canvass smoking clubs throughout the city.
走运的话 说不定有人见过马库斯和埃德加会面
Yeah. If we're lucky, somebody saw Marcus and Edgar meeting.
那台电脑呢
And what about that laptop?
海莉查出来病毒程序是谁创建的吗
Was Hayley able to identify who created that worm program?
还没
Not yet.
该死
Damn it.
你都弄好几个小时了
You've been working that thing for hours.
休息一下吧
You need to take a break.
这个埃德加肯定特别想致我于死地
Uh, this Edgar fellow has a serious hurt-on for me,
布莱斯也因此被连累死了
and he killed Bryce because of it.
那坏蛋不死我绝不休息
I'll take a break when that bastard is dead.
成功了
Hello. I'm in.
我破解了这病毒
I have unlocked the security for the worm.
怎么了
What is it?
我认得出这代码
I recognize this code.
你认识  怎么认识的
You do? How?
因为很久很久以前  我参与了它的设计
Because I helped design it a long, long time ago.
你说什么
W-What are you talking about?
该死
Damn it.
他电脑太垃圾了
His laptop is rubbish.
我需要一台更高配置的电脑
I'm gonna need something with more horsepower
来查个水落石出
in order to get to the bottom of this.
我去后面拿你的电脑过来
I'll get your laptop from the back.
你真好  谢啦
You're a dear. Thank you.
既然部分代码是你写的
Now, if it's partially your code,
应该能帮你缩小凶手的范围  对吧
then that should help narrow down who the killer is, right?
海莉
Hayley?
Hayley...
海莉
Hayley.
各位  我们有发现了
Hey, guys, we got something.
是的  从一个雪茄俱乐部得到消息
Yeah. One of those cigar clubs paid off.
经理认出了马库斯的照片
Manager recognized Marcus' photo.
他看见马库斯和谁在一起了吗
Did he see who Marcus was with?
他说马库斯是一个人去的
He said Marcus came in alone,
之后和一个穿棕色皮夹克的男子
and then he met with a guy in a brown leather jacket
大概聊了15分钟
for about 15 minutes.
他看清楚那个人的样子了吗
Did he get a good look at him?
没有  但是俱乐部里的监控录像拍下来了
No, but the club security cam did.
你们看  棕色皮夹克  一定是埃德加
Look -- brown leather jacket. Got to be Edgar.
这人看着眼熟
This guy looks familiar.
等一下
Hold on.
阿丽克西斯
Hey, Alexis.
爸爸  海莉跑了
Dad, Hayley's gone.
跑哪里去了
Gone where?
我不知道  她扔了手机
I don't know, but she ditched her cellphone.
我找不到她
I can't track her.
等一下  我开免提
Hang on. I'm putting you on speaker.
海莉失踪之前
What was the last thing
做的最后一件事情是什么
Hayley did before she disappeared?
她发现那个病毒
She discovered the computer worm
是多年前她帮忙设计的
was one she helped design years ago.
所以埃德加用海莉自己的代码来陷害她
So Edgar used Hayley's own code to help frame her.
她为什么要在真相大白时离开
Why did she take off right when she was closing in?
因为她知道凶手是谁
Because she knows who the killer is,
而且不叫埃德加
and his name isn't Edgar.
我调查了她去世的前搭档  韦斯利·康纳斯
I did some research on her dead MI6 partner, Wesley Connors,
发现了这篇六年前的文章
and I found this article from six years ago.
等一下
Wait a minute.
韦斯利·康纳斯就是那个穿棕色皮夹克的男子
Wesley Connors is the man in the brown leather jacket.
我就知道他看着眼熟
I knew he looked familiar.
这篇文章上说他被处死了
This article says he's been executed.
各位  海莉认出代码的时候
Guys, when Hayley recognized the code,
表情就像见鬼了一样
she looked like she'd just seen a ghost.
因为她确实见到鬼了
That's because she did.
韦斯利·康纳斯还活着
Wesley Connors is still alive.
有人吗
Hello?
韦斯
Wes.
出来吧  是我
Come on out. It's me.
成功了  海莉
It worked, Hails.
我们的计划终于实现了
Our plan worked.
这不可能
This is impossible.
韦斯利·康纳斯在伊朗被捉
Wesley Connors was caught and tried for espionage
并被判间谍罪
by the Iranians.
我们的情报部门确认他被处死了
Our intelligence sources confirmed he was executed.
显然  他们被骗了
Well, obviously, they were duped.
马洛里探员
Agent Mallory,
这个人攻击了伦敦电网
this man perpetrated an attack on the London power grid
还谋杀了两个人
and murdered two people,
你现在该配合我们了  告诉我们你知道什么
so it's time to play ball and tell us what you know.
我接下来要说的内容是绝密
What I'm about to tell you is highly classified
不可以外传
and mustn't be repeated.
明白了吗
Are we clear?
搞垮伦敦电网的病毒
The worm that crashed the London power grid
是海莉和韦斯利六年前
was a variation on one
设计的病毒的变种
Hayley and Wesley designed six years ago.
那是用来搞垮伊朗纳坦兹核反应堆的
It was used to knock out uranium-enriching centrifuges
铀浓缩离心机的
at the Natanz reactor in Iran.
你说的是震网病毒吗
Are you talking about Stuxnet?
那个让伊朗核项目
That computer virus
倒退了几十年的计算机病毒
set the Iranian nuclear program back by decades.
都说震网病毒是美国和以色列造的
Stuxnet was supposedly created by the U.S. And Israel.
假情报  警监
Disinformation, Captain,
是英国政府故意泄露的
leaked by Her Majesty's government.
和所有人一样  我们也想打击伊朗人
We wanted to hit the Iranians as much as everyone else,
所以我们派去了两个最好的特工
so we put our best two agents on it.
海莉和韦斯利
Hayley and Wesley.
由刚去世的布莱斯·罗伯茨领导
Led by the recently deceased Bryce Roberts.
这次行动成功了
The op was a success.
但他们的撤离点暴露了
However, their extraction point was compromised.
你说海莉扔下韦斯利等死
You said Hayley left Wesley to die.
是说过  我可能为了证明我的观点夸张了一点
Yes, well, I might have exaggerated a bit to make a point.
真相是  韦斯利没有准时到达集合地点
Truth is, Wesley was late to the rendezvous,
军情六处指挥部下令撤退的
and MI6 command made the call.
所以海莉才离开了军情六处
That's why Hayley left MI6.
她觉得他们背叛了韦斯利
She felt that they betrayed Wesley
导致了他的死亡
and condemned him to die.
所以我们现在陷入了困境
Which brings us to our current dilemma.
海莉和韦斯利交情甚密
Hayley and Wesley were thick as thieves,
他们对彼此的忠诚胜过情报局
more loyal to each other than the service.
你这是什么意思
What are you saying?
看样子他们是再次联手
That it would appear - they have teamed up once again
来报复我们
to have their retribution.
-你错了  -是吗  卡塞尔先生
- You're wrong. - Am I, Mr. Castle?
那么回答我  为什么海莉突然失踪了
Then, tell me, why has Hayley suddenly disappeared?
我不明白
I don't understand.
他们给我看了证据说你死了
They showed me proof you were dead.
我没死
No.
我倒是希望自己死了
I just wished I was.
他们对你做了什么
What did they do to you?
你了解我的
You know me.
我讨厌服从指挥  有时候我会拒绝
I hate taking orders, so sometimes I refused.
但他们从来不喜欢被拒绝
But they never liked that.
有时候我希望他们直接杀了我
Sometimes I wished they'd just finish me off.
有几次我试着自杀
There was times I tried to myself.
韦斯  我很抱歉
Wes, I'm sorry.
不要抱歉
Don't be.
你是支持我坚持下来的那个人
See, you're the person that got me through it all.
知道怎么回事吗
You know how?
我们的计划
Our plan.
它支撑着我度过了6年
It kept me going for six years,
给了我逃脱的意志
gave me the will to escape.
你一直说我们的计划  我
You keep saying "Our plan." I --
我们的退休计划  拜托  海莉
Our bloody retirement plan. Come on, Hails.
我们以前天天都在讨论
We used to talk all the time
如果我们能活到完成使命的那天
about how if we survived the Queen's service,
我们就用剩下的日子痛快地去环球旅行
we'd spend the rest of our days traveling the world in style.
你还记得吧
You remember.
-每人一千万美元  -对
- $10 million each. - Yeah.
你最近有查过你的银行账户吗
Have you checked your bank account lately?
现在你有了  我也有了
Now you have it, and so do I.
你通过了测试
You passed the test.
这就是一个忠诚测试吗
This was all a loyalty test?
这样才能知道你是否忠诚
It was the only way to know.
我必须得让你成为众矢之的
I had to put a target on your back
确保你不会向当局屈服
and make sure you wouldn't capitulate to the authorities,
你没有让我失望
but you didn't.
韦斯利  你杀人了  你杀了布莱斯
Wesley, you murdered people. You killed Bryce.
我当然杀人了
You're damn right I did!
他和我的祖国英国都抛弃了我
He and Her Majesty's Kingdom abandoned me,
他们应该得到惩罚
so they had to be punished.
所以你把我们的病毒发出去
Which is why you sent our worm
让伦敦陷入黑暗
to plunge London into darkness.
韦斯  那些伊朗人把你逼疯了
Oh, Wes, your captors drove you mad.
你怎么也这么说我呢
How can you of all people say that to me?
他们自找的
They had it coming.
他们全都是自找的
They all did.
你不明白吗
Don't you see that?
韦斯利  抱歉
Wesley, I'm sorry.
真的非常抱歉
I'm so, so sorry.
我必须把你带回去
I have to take you in.
集合地是预先决定好的
The rendezvous was predetermined.
因为海莉和韦斯利
Predetermined because Hayley and Wesley
相互勾结
are in league with one another.
他们现在没有合作
They are not working together.
但他们曾经合作过
But they were at one point.
他们是多年的搭档  合作过许多隐秘行动
They were partners for years, working various black ops,
也许在纽约也有过
maybe even one here in New York.
所以他们有以前的安全屋或者集结地
Where they had an old safehouse or a staging area,
一个他们都知道并信任的地方
someplace that they both knew about and could trust.
好吧  我既不能确认  也不能否认
Okay, look, I can neither confirm nor deny
军情六处在美国领土上实施过任何行动
MI6 has ever carried out any operations on U.S. Soil.
行行行  告诉我们在哪
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Just tell us where it is.
我很惊讶  海莉
I am shocked, Hayley.
以前我们针锋相对的时候
You always used to kick my ass
你总是对我毫不手软
whenever we sparred back in the day.
你想怎样  韦斯利
So, what's the plan, Wesley?
打算像他们折磨你一样折磨我吗
You gonna torture me like they did you?
我永远不会对朋友那样
I would never do that to a friend.
我会给你个痛快
I'll make it quick.
刚才还是有开心的  不是吗
It was fun for a moment, though, wasn't it?
我们重新在一起的想法
The thought of us together again.
你知道为什么我们能成为出色的间谍吗
Do you know why we were such effective spies?
因为  我们为任务的刺激而活着
Because we lived - for the rush of the mission.
我们愿意为了这种愉悦感去死
We were willing to die for that high.
然而我们错了
And we were wrong.
我们一生都不曾让别人了解过我们
After a lifetime of not letting anyone in,
甚至我们彼此也是这样
not even each other,
我找到了可以让我卸下心防的人
I found people who tore down my walls.
我找到了一个家庭  他们都是好人
I found a family, and they're wonderful.
所以我才把你吊在这
So that's why I gave you such a kicking.
你对我心软了  海莉
You've went and got soft on me, Hayley.
韦斯利  别这样  让我帮你
Wesley, don't do this. Let me help you.
帮我
Help me?
亲爱的  你现在连自己都帮不了
Love, you're not in a position to help yourself.
听着  我曾经是你的朋友
Listen, I was your friend once,
可以说是你一生中唯一的朋友
arguably the only one you've ever had in your entire life.
请让我再次成为你的朋友
Please let me be your friend once again.
我唯一需要的朋友是我的一千万美元
The only friend I need is my $10 million
也许还包括你的
and perhaps yours.
韦斯利  韦斯利
Wesley, Wesley...
韦斯利  不  不
Wesley. No, no.
韦斯利·康纳斯
Wesley Connors!
-纽约警察  -快把刀放下
- NYPD! Police! - Drop the knife now!
嘿
Hey!
放松  放松
Easy, easy.
-你没事吧  -嗯
- You okay? - Yeah.
这里有只有我和韦斯利知道的秘密出口
There are secret exits only Wesley and I know about.
他会原路返回  就此消失
He's gonna double back and disappear.
他们往那边去了
They went that way.
我们
We...
该死
Damn it.
韦斯利
Wesley.
让我看到你的手
Let me see your hands.
把刀放下
Drop the knife.
这是唯一的解决方法
There's only one way this is going to end.
-停下  -不是你死  就是我死
- Stop. - Either you die or I die.
韦斯利  别逼我这么做
Wesley, don't make me do this.
快点  海莉
Come on, Hails.
你已经杀过我一次了
You killed me once already.
别  我恨自己离开你
Don't. I hated myself for leaving you.
已经无法挽回了  亲爱的
Water under the bridge, darling.
接下来十秒无论发生什么  都不要后悔
And whatever happens in the next 10 seconds, no regrets.
对我来说  要么获得自由要么去死
For me, it's freedom or death.
韦斯利  别这样
Wesley, please.
再见  海莉
Goodbye, Hayley.
韦斯利  不要
Wesley, no!
海莉
Hayley.
你别无选择
You had no choice.
卡塞尔
Castle!
海莉
Hayley?
帮海莉在联调局把事情摆平真是干得漂亮
Nice job smoothing things over with the Feds for Hayley.
好吧  反正对他们来说
Yeah, well, it didn't hurt
能够了结一件恐怖案件
that they were able to take credit
而因此邀功  也不是什么坏事
for closing down a terrorism case, so --
重获光明
Oh, let there be light.
也太快了
That was fast.
因为海莉参与了那个病毒的创造
Well, since Hayley co-created the worm,
她知道怎么帮助英国政府打败它
she knew exactly how to help the U.K. Authorities defeat it.
这结局也是皆大欢喜了
All's well that ends well.
说到结局
Speaking of endings, I can't think
我想到个好办法来结束这一天
of a better way to end this day
我要跟我的得力警探一起喝几杯
than by downing a few ice-cold ones with my lead detectives.
-怎么样  -好
- How about it?  - Okay.
-你请客对吧  -是的  当然
- You're buying, right? - Yeah, exactly.
-好的  警监请客  -花警监的钱
- All right. Captain's money. - Got that captain's money.
干得好
Well done.
我听说你很喜欢纯麦芽威士忌
I heard you were single malt fans.
来自女王陛下的珍藏
From Her Majesty's special reserve.
她非常感谢各位谨慎行事
She truly appreciates everyone's discretion in this matter.
好吧  我们不想拂了女王的面子
W-Well, one does not want to insult the Queen.
我来还带了另一个礼物
I come bearing another gift --
一份复职邀请
an offer to return to service.
军情六处的大门为你敞开  希普顿探员
MI6's door is wide-open to you, Agent Shipton.
你觉得如何
What do you say?
我觉得
I say...
走开  朋友
piss off, mate.
如果你改变主意
Well, if you ever change your mind,
你知道怎么联系我们
you know where to find us.
希望渺茫  但还是要谢谢女王
Fat chance, but thank the Queen.
你还好吗
Hey...you all right?
当然  我很好
Sure. I'm fine.
知道吗  你不必独自缅怀旧友
You don't have to mourn your friends alone, you know?
从此也不必独自面对一切
You don't have to do anything alone ever again.
鲜花配美人
A red rose for the lady.
这是法语的"对不起"
You know, the French would say "Je suis désolé."
西班牙语"抱歉"
In Spanish, "Lo siento."
拉丁语"抱歉"
In Latin, "Mea culpa."
-好吧  你在道歉  我懂了  -对
- Okay, you're apologizing. I get it. - Yes.
因为我有事瞒着你
Because I have been keeping something from you
你的潜意识意识到了
that your subconscious mind picked up on
所以你才会梦见我背叛了你
and caused you to have a dream that I betrayed you in some way.
卡塞尔  我以为我们说好了
Castle, I thought that we said
不再有所隐瞒
we weren't gonna keep any more secrets.
我明白  我只是觉得
I know, and I just -- I consider this
这更像是个惊喜而不是秘密
more of a surprise than a secret.
但我早该明白
But I should have known better
而不是想要给世界上最伟大的警探惊喜
than to try and surprise the world's greatest detective,
除了蝙蝠侠以外
after Batman.
这块布后面是什么
W-What's behind the sheet?
凯特
Kate...
在过去的几年里
you've been going through a lot of changes
你的人生改变了许多
these past few years.
你搬了家  结了婚
You gave up your place, you got married,
还成为了一名警监
and you became a captain.
但有些你深爱的东西
But some of the things that you love
也被搁在了一边
have fallen by the wayside,
其中有一样东西
including one thing that's been gathering dust
在你父亲的车库里都积了灰
in your father's garage.
-你不会是...  -是的
- You didn't? - I did.
我把它完全修好了
I had it completely restored.
我...
I...
来  坐上去
Yeah, sit on it.
这...我...我
What, I-I just...
我想你该骑上这辆摩托来一个全国旅行
I think you should take the bike on a cross-country trip.
这是你一直都想做的事
It's something - you've always wanted to do.
太棒了
This is amazing.
我好喜欢
I love this.
但我不想自己一个人去
But I-I don't want to do this alone.
要不你去上点课学一下
Why don't you get some lessons?
我就盼着你这么说
I was hoping you'd say that,
因为我已经拿到驾照然后买了一辆
because I already got my license and I bought a bike.
就在办公室的车库里
It's at the garage to the office.
我爱你
I love you.
这是不是就意味着
Does this mean that you won't be having
你今晚再也不会做关于我的噩梦了
any more bad dreams about me tonight?
不会  因为我们今晚要不眠不休
No, 'cause we're not sleeping tonight.
把头盔带上
Bring the helmet.
安全第一
Safety first.